being a student is often a very
important phase in a person's life
however studying is a full-time
occupation and so students who are
looking to earn a bit of money start
searching for part-time jobs that don't
affect their studies
concerns for students are how to earn
money online without making a large
investment or finding jobs that require
minimal experience
and here's the good news
there are actually a number of online
part-time jobs for students where they
can earn money at home
what are the best ways to earn money
online as a student
one
sell insurance as a post becoming a posp
or point of salesperson and selling
insurance can be a lucrative part-time
job for students
aposp is an insurance agent who works
with an insurance company to sell their
insurance products online
what are the requirements you must be
over 18 years of age and should have
completed class 10.
you also need to complete a 15-hour
compulsory training offered by the urbai
how much can you earn your income would
depend on the number of policies you
sell
thus the more policies you sell the more
income you will earn
can you continue this job
yes if you have an aptitude for selling
you can continue this later as a
full-time job
find out more about the steps
requirements and regulations for
becoming a posp agent here
two take up freelancing
if you are someone who is good at
writing programming editing photography
designing or any other such skills you
can earn money online as a freelancer
you just need to register yourself as a
freelancer on portals like upwork fiverr
or truelancer
then you can start marketing your skills
to potential clients
what are the requirements as long as you
have a marketable skill you can register
on a freelancing portal though this may
require a small fee
how much can you earn your income will
be based on the kind of work you offer
and how much work you have time to do
can you continue this job
yes based on the kind of work you offer
you can continue to work full time as a
freelancer
three start tutoring online students are
constantly learning new things so one
easy way to earn money online is to
share some of this knowledge
whether you want to tutor school
children or provide courses for adults
who want to learn something new all you
need is access to a fast internet
connection
you can either sign up with a virtual
tutoring platform like udemy skillshare
or coursera or simply reach out on
social media to friends and relative
circles to broadcast your online
tutoring classes
do micro jobs online
one of the best ways for students to
earn some extra cash is by doing small
tasks or offering small services to
businesses and people on a micro gig
site
there are many reputable micro job sites
you can join to advertise your skills
and services by posting any job that you
can do or service you can sell for a
fixed amount of money for each job done
or service provided
you can use micro gig sites to offer
different types of freelance services or
to do different types of jobs via your
computer
you can do micro gigs for various
services such as
writing for companies and people
editing articles academic papers etc
designing websites designing logos video
editing
social media marketing maintaining
social media profiles
seo services you can even offer to sing
a happy birthday song create funny
videos of yourself and do more
off-the-wall tasks marketing your skills
is critical to reach out to your
potential clients
landing the first job is important as
one job will lead to another sooner or
later
if a client likes your work and leaves
good feedback you can attract more
clients
you can get more orders from existing
clients if they were happy with your
previous work
popular micro gig sites include
fiverr jigbox 5 squids 10 bucks zerf
tenor
seo clerks
blocking could be a nice way for
students to earn some extra cash
if you have a favorite hobby you can
just write content about it and share
your content with others
you can blog about an academic subject
or more you have good knowledge in or
write about non-academic topics on your
blog
once your blog starts getting some
traffic you can use a number of ways to
monetize your blog
if you write quality posts on your blog
on a regular basis you will be able to
attract a lot of users to your blog
students can run and maintain a blog in
their spare time
a blog with a steady amount of traffic
can earn a solid side income regularly
to get started
choose a domain name that relates to
your blog
register your blog with a reputable
domain registration company design your
blog yourself or hire a freelance web
designer to do it
by hosting service to publish your site
on the web
promote your blog using various
marketing channels
monetize your blog
final thoughts on ways students earn
money online
making money online is entirely
practicable for students
you just need to make sure that whatever
job you want to do or service you want
to offer you are good at that by earning
money online doing an online job or more
students can pay down their student
loans pay bills save for buying an
expensive gift and achieve any other
financial goal
you